<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Export generator="IRIS" version="26">
<Global>
<Node><Sub>^%ZAPM.bs.BSCGER</Sub>
<Data>ТЕКСТЫ ПРЕРЫВАНИЙ ВЫПОЛНЕНИЯ ПРОГРАММ</Data>
<Node><Sub>&lt;BLOCKNUMBER</Sub>
<Data>  A reference has been made to a block outside the range of the database file.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CANNOT GET THIS PROPERTY</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to get a property of a class for which getting this property is invalid.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CANNOT SET THIS PROPERTY</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to set a property of a class for which setting this property is invalid.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS COMPILING</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to instantiate a class or invoke a class method of a class which is currently being recompiled on the local system.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS DESCRIPTOR</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to run a routine which is actually a class descriptor.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS DOES NOT EXIST</Sub>
<Data>  A reference has been made to a nonexistent class.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS EDITED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use an object hosted on the local system whose class has been recompiled from a remote system since the object was created.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS RECOMPILED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use an object hosted on the local system whose class has been recompiled on the local system since the object was created.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS TOO BIG TO LOAD</Sub>
<Data>  A class cannot be used because its class descriptor is too large to fit into a routine buffer.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLASS TOO BIG TO SAVE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A class cannot be created because its class descriptor is too large to fit into a routine buffer.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLIENT-SERVER MISMATCH</Sub>
<Data>  A network request cannot be processed due to incompatibility between the client and server.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CLUSTERFAIL</Sub>
<Data>  A cluster member has failed during global buffer lock processing.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;COLLATEMISMATCH</Sub>
<Data>  Subscript level mapping failed due to misconfigured collation type.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;COLLATION NOT SUPPORTED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A reference has been made to a global whose collation type is not supported on the current system.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;COMMAND</Sub>
<Data>НЕДОПУСТИМАЯ КОМАНДА</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;COMMITFAIL</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Received during a COMMIT when Cache receives an error while processing a TCommit. This error means that Cache is not sure whether one or more remote machines actually processed the commit.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CONFLICTING BLOCK NUMBERS</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to reserve a block that was already reserved.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CORRUPT OBJECT</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  An internal object system error occurred. Contact InterSystems Worldwide Response Center if this error occurs.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CORRUPT VOLUME SET</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The volume set is corrupted. Usually, this means the label on the volume set is wrong. Use the LABEL utility to correct it.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;CP NOT STARTED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  One of the major processes required for proper operation of the system failed to start. This is potentially a very serious system error; notify your system manager.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DATABASE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache has detected degradation in this database (this is potentially a very serious system error; notify your system manager).  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DATABASE MAP LABEL</Sub>
<Data>  There is an invalid label in a database map block.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DIRECTORY</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There is no such directory on the target system, no Cache database, the Cache database is not mounted, or the database is locked by another configuration.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DISCONNECT</Sub>
<Data>  A TCP disconnect has been detected while a long-duration request is being processed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DISKHARD</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache has encountered an uncorrectable disk hardware error (this may also be the result of a database problem; notify your system manager).  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DIVIDE</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to divide by zero.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DOMAINSPACERETRY</Sub>
<Data>  Repeated attempts to contact the domain space master have failed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DSCON</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to read from a disconnected terminal.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;DYNAMIC LIBRARY LOAD</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  An error has occurred during an attempt to load a dynamic library via callout. See cconsole.log for additional information.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ECODETRAP</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A user-generated software trap was generated by setting the $ECODE system variable to a non-null string value.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;EDITED</Sub>
<Data>ВЫПОЛНЯЕМАЯ ПРОГРАММА ПОДВЕРГЛАСЬ РЕДАКТИРОВАНИЮ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ENDOFFILE</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to read past the end-of-file marker of a sequential file.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;FILEFULL</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache attempted to allocate a disk block for more global data or routine storage, but the attempt failed because the Cache database is full and could not be expanded.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;FRAMESTACK</Sub>
<Data>ПЕРЕПОЛНЕНИЕ СТЭКА ПРОГРАММЫ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;FUNCTION</Sub>
<Data>  The specified function does not exist or is being used improperly.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;GARBAGE COLLECTOR FAILED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The one of the processes that reclaims space in the database hase failed. This is potentially a very serious system error; notify your system manager.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;HALTED</Sub>
<Data>  An internal error message.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ILLEGAL VALUE</Sub>
<Data>НЕДОПУСТИМОЕ ЗНАЧЕНИЕ В ИНДЕКСЕ ПЕРЕМЕННОЙ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INSUFFICIENT CLASS MEMORY</Sub>
<Data>  A class cannot be used because Cache has run out of shared memory.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INTERNAL OBJECT ERROR</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  An internal object system error. Contact InterSystems Worldwide Response Center if this error occurs.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INTERRUPT</Sub>
<Data>  A user has interrupted the routine. (In many implementations, the user has pressed CTRL-C.)  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INVALID ARGUMENT</Sub>
<Data>  There is an invalid argument prototype in the zfentry specification of a callout function.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INVALID BIT STRING</Sub>
<Data>  The bit string used in a bit string operation is not valid.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INVALID CLASS</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use a class that has been corrupted. Recompile the class and try again.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INVALID OREF</Sub>
<Data>  No object with the specified OREF is currently in memory.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;INVALID TYPE</Sub>
<Data>  An OREF has been used where not allowed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;Java Exception</Sub>
<Data>  An exception occurred during a call into the Java runtime environment.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;Java VM not loaded</Sub>
<Data>  No Java Virtual Machine is available.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LABELREDEF</Sub>
<Data>ДУБЛИРОВАНИЕ МЕТОК В ПРОГРАММЕ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LANGUAGE MISMATCH</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  While compiling and inserting code into an existing routine, the current language mode differs from that of the routine.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LICENSE LIMIT EXCEEDED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to exceed the number of processes allowed on your system under the current license.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LICENSE SERVER UNAVAILABLE</Sub>
<Data>  The license server is unreachable at the moment. Check your network.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LIST</Sub>
<Data>  An improperly-formed list has been used.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LOCKLOST</Sub>
<Data>  Some locks once owned by this job have been reset.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;LOGIN INHIBITED</Sub>
<Data>  The system is initializing. No users are permitted to begin work.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MAGTAPE</Sub>
<Data>  A magnetic tape operation encountered an error. Check $ZA.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MAXARRAY</Sub>
<Data>  There are too many subscripts at this level.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MAXNUMBER</Sub>
<Data>  An arithmetic operation has produced a number larger than the implementation allows.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MAXSCOPE</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to issue more than 31 levels of New commands.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MAXSTRING</Sub>
<Data>ПРЕВЫШЕНИЕ ДЛИНЫ ПЕРЕМЕННОЙ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;METHOD DOES NOT EXIST</Sub>
<Data>  The method does not exist in the specified class or the class of the specified object.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;MNEMONICSPACE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use control mnemonics for a device with no associated mnemonic space.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NAKED</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to use a naked global reference when the naked state was undefined.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NAME</Sub>
<Data>  There is invalid syntax in a name.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NAMEADD</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an overflow of device name table, resulting from the Open command.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NAMESPACE</Sub>
<Data>НЕСУЩЕСТВУЩАЯ ИМЕННАЯ ОБЛАСТЬ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETFORMAT</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an error in a network message. The remote system found fault with the format of a request. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETGLOREF</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an error in a network message. The remote system found fault with the format of a request. Call your support center to resolve this serious error. (This can also occur if a remote global is a string-collated or 7-bit encoded global on a DSM system.)  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETJOBMAX</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Another high-speed networking process cannot be added. This is usually due to an insufficient number of global buffers.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETLOCK</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A Cache ObjectScript Lock command has been attempted to a remote computer whose remote system index is greater than 31. To correct, redefine your network configuration to include fewer than 32 remote computers.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETRETRY</Sub>
<Data>  An operation failed at the network level in a way that could be immediately retried.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETSRVFAIL</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  During a transaction COMMIT or a Set, Kill, ZKill command, a client system has detected that one of the servers involved in the transaction has restarted while the transaction was open. Cache  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETVERSION</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The client and server systems are running different DDP versions, which cannot accept each other's message format.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Typically, one of the following has occurred: the network timeout has expired; the local port has gone down; the node being accessed is down; or the remote server connection is disabled.   ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost. The reasons for the loss are undetermined. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - BLOCKNUMBER</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because the remote system attempted to refer to a block that is outside the bounds of the database; notify your system manager.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - CLIENT-SERVER MISMATCH</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because a network request could not be processed due to incompatibility between the client and server.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - CLUSTERFAILED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because a cluster member failed during global buffer lock processing.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - DATABASE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because Cache on the server has detected degradation in this database. This is potentially a very serious system error; notify your system manager.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - DIRECTORY</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because the referenced directory is not on the remote system.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - DISKHARD</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because Cache on the server has encountered an uncorrectable disk hardware error. This may also be the result of a database problem; notify your system manager.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - FILEFULL</Sub>
<Data>  In networked operation, a &lt;FILEFULL&gt; error occurred.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - MAXSTRING</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to specify or create a data string longer than the implementation allows (32,767 characters).  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - NETFORMAT</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because the remote system found fault with the format of a request. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - NETGLOREF</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because the remote system found fault with the format of a request. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - NETVERSION</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The client and server systems are running different ECP versions, which cannot accept each other's message format.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - PROTECT</Sub>
<Data>  In networked operation, a &lt;PROTECT&gt; error occurred.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - STRINGSTACK</Sub>
<Data>  In networked operation, a &lt;STRINGSTACK&gt; error occurred.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - STRMISMATCH</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because there has been an internal error handling big strings over the network.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - SUBSCRIPT</Sub>
<Data>  In networked operation, a &lt;SUBSCRIPT&gt; error occurred.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - SYSTEM</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Updates sent over the network were lost because a <SYSTEM> error occurred on the server. Either there has been an attempt to do something not allowed by the operating system or ECP. Or there is an error condition in Cache, in which case you should notify your support center with as much information as possible.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NETWORK DATA UPDATE FAILED - WIDECHAR</Sub>
<Data>  In networked operation, a &lt;WIDECHAR&gt; error occurred.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NLS TABLE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to perform NLS translation using data that is not proper for the conversion table.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NO CURRENT OBJECT</Sub>
<Data>  There is no current object.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NO MAILBOX</Sub>
<Data>  A resource needed for inter-process communication is unavailable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NO SOURCE</Sub>
<Data>  A source line is missing from a routine in the routine source global.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NODEV</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to a write-only device, or write to a read-only device, with interjob communication.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOJOB</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to specify an incorrect process number in a View command, or an error occurred in a Job command.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOLINE</Sub>
<Data>НЕСУЩЕСТВУЮЩАЯ МЕТКА В ПРОГРАММЕ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOROUTINE</Sub>
<Data>НЕСУЩЕСТВУЮЩАЯ ПРОГРАММА</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOSYS</Sub>
<Data>НЕСУЩЕСТВУЮЩАЯ ИМЕННАЯ ОБЛАСТЬ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOT PRIMARY VOLUME</Sub>
<Data>  Volume sequence is not 1; the volume label disagrees with the function of the volume.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NOTOPEN</Sub>
<Data>УСТРОЙСТВО НЕ ОТКРЫТО</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;NULL VALUE</Sub>
<Data>  A null string appears where one is not allowed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;OUT OF $ZF HEAP SPACE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The $ZF heap lacks the necessary available space to support one of the input or output parameters being passed between Cache and the external program invoked via the $ZF function.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PARAMET</Sub>
<Data>ОТСУТСТВЕТ СПИСОК ФОРМАЛЬНЫХ ПЕРЕМЕННЫХ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PARAMETER</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  The number of parameters passed to a labeled line by a user-written function reference or a Do command exceeded the number of formal parameters declared for the labeled line.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PRIVATE METHOD</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to invoke a private and, therefore, unavailable method.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PRIVATE PROPERTY</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to access a private and, therefore, unavailable property.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PROPERTY DOES NOT EXIST</Sub>
<Data>  The property is not part of the class of the specified object.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;PROTECT</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to do something with a global (Read, Write, or Kill) for which there was no authorization; or there has been an attempt to use a View command which modifies memory, $View, $ZU(49), or $ZU(58); or there has been an attempt to use a nonexistent directory, possibly with extended global syntax, or some other protection violation occurred.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;RANGE</Sub>
<Data>  A bit position is out of allowable range.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;READ</Sub>
<Data>  The record cannot be read.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;RECOMPILE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A routine has been compiled under a different version of Cache or an InterSystems legacy product. It cannot be loaded onto this system with %RIMF, which transfers object code. Transfer it as source code (using %RO and %RI, or the Cache Explorer) and then recompile it.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;REMOTE CLASS EDITED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use an object hosted on a remote system whose class has been recompiled from a remote system since the object was created.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;REMOTE CLASS RECOMPILED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use an object hosted on a remote system whose class has been recompiled from the local system since the object was created.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ROLLFAIL</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache has encountered an error processing a call to TRollBack. This error means that Cache is not sure whether one or more remote machines actually processed the rollback.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ROUTINELOAD</Sub>
<Data>  An error occurred in loading a routine. This is database degradation; notify the system manager.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;SELECT</Sub>
<Data>  A $Select function contains no true condition.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;SLMSPAN</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to kill a global across a subscript level mapping boundary.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;STACK</Sub>
<Data>  The argument stack is out of room or contains an incorrect type.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;STORE</Sub>
<Data>ПЕРЕПОЛНЕНИЕ ОБЛАСТИ ЛОКАЛЬНЫХ ПЕРЕМЕННЫХ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;STRINGSTACK</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  An expression is too long, there are too many expressions in an argument for a single command, or an expression contains many very long strings. Simplify the expression.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;STRMISMATCH</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an internal error handling big strings over the network.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;SUBSCRIPT</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A subscript has an illegal value or a global reference is too long. If a global reference is too long, then either (1) the encoded length of an individual subscript exceeds 255 bytes or (2) the sum of the encoded lengths of the following items exceeds 512 bytes: the length of the global name; the lengths of all subscripts; the number of subscripts; the number of numeric subscripts; and the number of negative numeric subscripts.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;SYNTAX</Sub>
<Data>СИНТАКСИЧЕСКАЯ ОШИБКА В ПРОГРАММЕ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;SYSTEM</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Either there has been an attempt to do something not allowed by the operating system, or there is an error condition in Cache, in which case you should notify your support center with as much information as possible.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TERMINATOR</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to read on a terminal or device in image mode with no terminator and it was not a fixed-length read.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TOO MANY CLASSES</Sub>
<Data>  This process has attempted to access too many active classes.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TOO MANY OREFS</Sub>
<Data>  This process has attempted to create too many simultaneously open objects.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TOO MANY USERS</Sub>
<Data>  Too many users are attempting to use the system at the same time.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TOO MANY USERS OF CLASS</Sub>
<Data>  Too many processes are trying to use a particular class simultaneously (more than 65561).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TOOMANYFILES</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache is unable to open a file because the underlying operating system has run out of file descriptors.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TRANSLATE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  Cache has read an input value for which it has no translation value. It therefore carries out the Default Action defined on the Translation tab of the Cache NLS utility.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;TRANSLOST</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  A distributed transaction initiated by this job has been asynchronously rolled back by the server.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;UNDEFINED</Sub>
<Data>НЕОПРЕДЕЛЕННАЯ ПЕРЕМЕННАЯ</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;UNIMPLEMENTED</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been an attempt to use either an unimplemented function or an unimplemented argument of a legitimate command or function.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;UNKNOWN ERROR</Sub>
<Data>  An unexpected error has occurred. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;VALUE OUT OF RANGE</Sub>
<Data>  The value is outside the maximum or minimum permissible range.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;VOLUME IS NOT FORMATTED</Sub>
<Data>  The volume does not have the required formatting.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;VOLUME SET ALREADY CREATED</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to format an Cache database that is already formatted.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;WIDE CHAR</Sub>
<Data>  Cache read a multibyte character where a 1-byte character was expected.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;WRITE</Sub>
<Data>ОШИБКА ЗАПИСИ НА ТЕКУЩЕЕ УСТРОЙСТВО</Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;WRITE DEMON FAILED</Sub>
<Data>  The write daemon is unable to continue. Call your support center to resolve this serious error.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZFILE</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been a file-related problem, such as that a file cannot be found or cannot be opened; consult the error log for more details.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZMISC</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  An error has occurred of a different type than the others listed in this table. More detail follows the <ZMISC> code itself.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZOPEN</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an error opening a device with TCP; the database server being shadowed is down.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZREAD</Sub>
<Data><![CDATA[  There has been a failure to read from the database server that is being shadowed, indicating that the server is disconnected or not currently running.  ]]></Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZSTOP</Sub>
<Data>  Shadowing has been stopped by system shutdown or the user.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>&lt;ZTRAP</Sub>
<Data>  There has been an attempt to issue a ZTrap command with no argument.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M1</Sub>
<Data> Naked indicator undefined.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M10</Sub>
<Data> Invalid pattern match range.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M11</Sub>
<Data> No parameters passed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M12</Sub>
<Data> Invalid line reference (negative offset).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M13</Sub>
<Data> Invalid line reference (line not found).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M14</Sub>
<Data> Line level not one (1).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M15</Sub>
<Data> Undefined index variable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M16</Sub>
<Data> Quit with an argument not allowed.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M17</Sub>
<Data> Quit with an argument required.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M18</Sub>
<Data> Fixed-length Read not greater than 0 (zero).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M19</Sub>
<Data> Cannot merge a tree or subtree into itself.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M2</Sub>
<Data> Invalid $FNumber code string combination.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M20</Sub>
<Data> Line must have a formal list.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M21</Sub>
<Data> Formal list name duplication.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M22</Sub>
<Data> Set or Kill to ^$Global structured system variable name (SSVN) when data in global.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M23</Sub>
<Data> Set or Kill to ^$Job structured system variable name (SSVN) for non-existent job number.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M24</Sub>
<Data> Change to collation algorithm while subscripted local variables defined.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M26</Sub>
<Data> Non-existent environment (non-existent namespace).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M27</Sub>
<Data> Attempt to roll back a transaction that is not re-startable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M28</Sub>
<Data> Mathematical function, parameter out of range.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M29</Sub>
<Data> Set or Kill on structured system variable name (SSVN) not allowed by implementation.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M3</Sub>
<Data> $Random argument less than 1.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M30</Sub>
<Data> Reference to global variable with different collating sequence within a collating algorithm.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M31</Sub>
<Data> Device control mnemonic expression used for a device without a mnemonic space being selected.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M32</Sub>
<Data> Device control mnemonic used in user-defined mnemonic space which has no associated line.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M33</Sub>
<Data> Set or Kill to ^$Routine when the routine specified exists.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M35</Sub>
<Data> Device does not support mnemonic spaces.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M36</Sub>
<Data> Incompatible mnemonic spaces.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M37</Sub>
<Data> Read from device identified by null string.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M38</Sub>
<Data> Invalid structured system variable name (SSVN) subscript.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M39</Sub>
<Data> Invalid $Name argument.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M4</Sub>
<Data> No true condition in $Select.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M40</Sub>
<Data> Call by reference in the actual parameter list in Job command.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M41</Sub>
<Data> Invalid Lock argument within a transaction.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M42</Sub>
<Data> Invalid Quit within a transaction.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M43</Sub>
<Data> Invalid range value ($X,$Y).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M44</Sub>
<Data> Invalid command outside a transaction.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M45</Sub>
<Data> Invalid GoTo reference.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M5</Sub>
<Data> Line reference less than 0 (zero).  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M57</Sub>
<Data> A label is defined more than once in a routine.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M58</Sub>
<Data> Too few formal parameters.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M6</Sub>
<Data> Undefined local variable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M7</Sub>
<Data> Undefined global variable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M8</Sub>
<Data> Undefined special variable.  </Data>
</Node>
<Node><Sub>M9</Sub>
<Data> Divide by zero.  </Data>
</Node>
</Node>
</Global>
</Export>
